Name

glAttachShader — Attaches a shader object to a program object

C Specification

void glAttachShader( | GLuint   | program,
  | GLuint   | shader);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object to which a shader object will be attached.

shader

Specifies the shader object that is to be attached.

Description

In order to create an executable, there must be a way to specify the list of things that will be linked together. Program objects provide this mechanism. Shaders that are to be linked together in a program object must first be attached to that program object. glAttachShader attaches the shader object specified by shader to the program object specified by program. This indicates that shader will be included in link operations that will be performed on program.

All operations that can be performed on a shader object are valid whether or not the shader object is attached to a program object. It is permissible to attach a shader object to a program object before source code has been loaded into the shader object or before the shader object has been compiled. It is permissible to attach multiple shader objects of the same type because each may contain a portion of the complete shader. It is also permissible to attach a shader object to more than one program object. If a shader object is deleted while it is attached to a program object, it will be flagged for deletion, and deletion will not occur until glDetachShader is called to detach it from all program objects to which it is attached.

Notes

glAttachShader is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if either program or shader is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if shader is not a shader object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if shader is already attached to program.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glAttachShader is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetAttachedShaders with the handle of a valid program object

glIsProgram

glIsShader

See Also

glCompileShader, glDetachShader, glLinkProgram, glShaderSource

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glBindAttribLocation — Associates a generic vertex attribute index with a named attribute variable

C Specification

void glBindAttribLocation( | GLuint   | program,
  | GLuint   | index,
  | const GLchar *  | name);

Parameters

program

Specifies the handle of the program object in which the association is to be made.

index

Specifies the index of the generic vertex attribute to be bound.

name

Specifies a null terminated string containing the name of the vertex shader attribute variable to which index is to be bound.

Description

glBindAttribLocation is used to associate a user-defined attribute variable in the program object specified by program with a generic vertex attribute index. The name of the user-defined attribute variable is passed as a null terminated string in name. The generic vertex attribute index to be bound to this variable is specified by index. When program is made part of current state, values provided via the generic vertex attribute index will modify the value of the user-defined attribute variable specified by name.

If name refers to a matrix attribute variable, index refers to the first column of the matrix. Other matrix columns are then automatically bound to locations index+1 for a matrix of type mat2; index+1 and index+2 for a matrix of type mat3; and index+1, index+2, and index+3 for a matrix of type mat4.

This command makes it possible for vertex shaders to use descriptive names for attribute variables rather than generic variables that are numbered from 0 to GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS -1. The values sent to each generic attribute index are part of current state, just like standard vertex attributes such as color, normal, and vertex position. If a different program object is made current by calling glUseProgram, the generic vertex attributes are tracked in such a way that the same values will be observed by attributes in the new program object that are also bound to index.

Attribute variable name-to-generic attribute index bindings for a program object can be explicitly assigned at any time by calling glBindAttribLocation. Attribute bindings do not go into effect until glLinkProgram is called. After a program object has been linked successfully, the index values for generic attributes remain fixed (and their values can be queried) until the next link command occurs.

Applications are not allowed to bind any of the standard OpenGL vertex attributes using this command, as they are bound automatically when needed. Any attribute binding that occurs after the program object has been linked will not take effect until the next time the program object is linked.

Notes

glBindAttribLocation is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

glBindAttribLocation can be called before any vertex shader objects are bound to the specified program object. It is also permissible to bind a generic attribute index to an attribute variable name that is never used in a vertex shader.

If name was bound previously, that information is lost. Thus you cannot bind one user-defined attribute variable to multiple indices, but you can bind multiple user-defined attribute variables to the same index.

Applications are allowed to bind more than one user-defined attribute variable to the same generic vertex attribute index. This is called aliasing, and it is allowed only if just one of the aliased attributes is active in the executable program, or if no path through the shader consumes more than one attribute of a set of attributes aliased to the same location. The compiler and linker are allowed to assume that no aliasing is done and are free to employ optimizations that work only in the absence of aliasing. OpenGL implementations are not required to do error checking to detect aliasing. Because there is no way to bind standard attributes, it is not possible to alias generic attributes with conventional ones (except for generic attribute 0).

Active attributes that are not explicitly bound will be bound by the linker when glLinkProgram is called. The locations assigned can be queried by calling glGetAttribLocation.

OpenGL copies the name string when glBindAttribLocation is called, so an application may free its copy of the name string immediately after the function returns.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if index is greater than or equal to GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if name starts with the reserved prefix "gl_".

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glBindAttribLocation is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS

glGetActiveAttrib with argument program

glGetAttribLocation with arguments program and name

glIsProgram

See Also

glDisableVertexAttribArray, glEnableVertexAttribArray, glUseProgram, glVertexAttrib, glVertexAttribPointer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glCreateShader — Creates a shader object

C Specification

GLuint glCreateShader( | GLenum   | shaderType);

Parameters

shaderType

Specifies the type of shader to be created. Must be either GL_VERTEX_SHADER or GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER.

Description

glCreateShader creates an empty shader object and returns a non-zero value by which it can be referenced. A shader object is used to maintain the source code strings that define a shader. shaderType indicates the type of shader to be created. Two types of shaders are supported. A shader of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER is a shader that is intended to run on the programmable vertex processor and replace the fixed functionality vertex processing in OpenGL. A shader of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER is a shader that is intended to run on the programmable fragment processor and replace the fixed functionality fragment processing in OpenGL.

When created, a shader object's GL_SHADER_TYPE parameter is set to either GL_VERTEX_SHADER or GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER, depending on the value of shaderType.

Notes

glCreateShader is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Like display lists and texture objects, the name space for shader objects may be shared across a set of contexts, as long as the server sides of the contexts share the same address space. If the name space is shared across contexts, any attached objects and the data associated with those attached objects are shared as well.

Applications are responsible for providing the synchronization across API calls when objects are accessed from different execution threads.

Errors

This function returns 0 if an error occurs creating the shader object.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if shaderType is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glCreateShader is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetShader with a valid shader object and the parameter to be queried

glGetShaderInfoLog with a valid shader object

glGetShaderSource with a valid shader object

glIsShader

See Also

glAttachShader, glCompileShader, glDeleteShader, glDetachShader, glShaderSource

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glDrawBuffers — Specifies a list of color buffers to be drawn into

C Specification

void glDrawBuffers( | GLsizei   | n,
  | const GLenum *  | bufs);

Parameters

n

Specifies the number of buffers in bufs.

bufs

Points to an array of symbolic constants specifying the buffers into which fragment colors or data values will be written.

Description

glDrawBuffers defines an array of buffers into which fragment color values or fragment data will be written. If no fragment shader is active, rendering operations will generate only one fragment color per fragment and it will be written into each of the buffers specified by bufs. If a fragment shader is active and it writes a value to the output variable gl_FragColor, then that value will be written into each of the buffers specified by bufs. If a fragment shader is active and it writes a value to one or more elements of the output array variable gl_FragData[], then the value of gl_FragData[0] will be written into the first buffer specified by bufs, the value of gl_FragData[1] will be written into the second buffer specified by bufs, and so on up to gl_FragData[n-1]. The draw buffer used for gl_FragData[n] and beyond is implicitly set to be GL_NONE.

The symbolic constants contained in bufs may be any of the following:

GL_NONE

The fragment color/data value is not written into any color buffer.

GL_FRONT_LEFT

The fragment color/data value is written into the front left color buffer.

GL_FRONT_RIGHT

The fragment color/data value is written into the front right color buffer.

GL_BACK_LEFT

The fragment color/data value is written into the back left color buffer.

GL_BACK_RIGHT

The fragment color/data value is written into the back right color buffer.

GL_AUXi

The fragment color/data value is written into auxiliary buffer i.

Except for GL_NONE, the preceding symbolic constants may not appear more than once in bufs. The maximum number of draw buffers supported is implementation dependent and can be queried by calling glGet with the argument GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS. The number of auxiliary buffers can be queried by calling glGet with the argument GL_AUX_BUFFERS.

Notes

glDrawBuffers is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

It is always the case that GL_AUXi = GL_AUX0 + i.

The symbolic constants GL_FRONT, GL_BACK, GL_LEFT, GL_RIGHT, and GL_FRONT_AND_BACK are not allowed in the bufs array since they may refer to multiple buffers.

If a fragment shader writes to neither gl_FragColor nor gl_FragData, the values of the fragment colors following shader execution are undefined. For each fragment generated in this situation, a different value may be written into each of the buffers specified by bufs.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if one of the values in bufs is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if n is less than 0.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if a symbolic constant other than GL_NONE appears more than once in bufs.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if any of the entries in bufs (other than GL_NONE ) indicates a color buffer that does not exist in the current GL context.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if n is greater than GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glDrawBuffers is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_DRAW_BUFFERS

glGet with argument GL_DRAW_BUFFERSi where i indicates the number of the draw buffer whose value is to be queried

See Also

glBlendFunc, glColorMask, glDrawBuffers, glIndexMask, glLogicOp, glReadBuffer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetActiveAttrib — Returns information about an active attribute variable for the specified program object

C Specification

void glGetActiveAttrib( | GLuint   | program,
  | GLuint   | index,
  | GLsizei   | bufSize,
  | GLsizei *  | length,
  | GLint *  | size,
  | GLenum *  | type,
  | GLchar *  | name);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object to be queried.

index

Specifies the index of the attribute variable to be queried.

bufSize

Specifies the maximum number of characters OpenGL is allowed to write in the character buffer indicated by name.

length

Returns the number of characters actually written by OpenGL in the string indicated by name (excluding the null terminator) if a value other than NULL is passed.

size

Returns the size of the attribute variable.

type

Returns the data type of the attribute variable.

name

Returns a null terminated string containing the name of the attribute variable.

Description

glGetActiveAttrib returns information about an active attribute variable in the program object specified by program. The number of active attributes can be obtained by calling glGetProgram with the value GL_ACTIVE_ATTRIBUTES. A value of 0 for index selects the first active attribute variable. Permissible values for index range from 0 to the number of active attribute variables minus 1.

A vertex shader may use either built-in attribute variables, user-defined attribute variables, or both. Built-in attribute variables have a prefix of "gl_" and reference conventional OpenGL vertex attribtes (e.g., gl_Vertex, gl_Normal, etc., see the OpenGL Shading Language specification for a complete list.) User-defined attribute variables have arbitrary names and obtain their values through numbered generic vertex attributes. An attribute variable (either built-in or user-defined) is considered active if it is determined during the link operation that it may be accessed during program execution. Therefore, program should have previously been the target of a call to glLinkProgram, but it is not necessary for it to have been linked successfully.

The size of the character buffer required to store the longest attribute variable name in program can be obtained by calling glGetProgram with the value GL_ACTIVE_ATTRIBUTE_MAX_LENGTH. This value should be used to allocate a buffer of sufficient size to store the returned attribute name. The size of this character buffer is passed in bufSize, and a pointer to this character buffer is passed in name.

glGetActiveAttrib returns the name of the attribute variable indicated by index, storing it in the character buffer specified by name. The string returned will be null terminated. The actual number of characters written into this buffer is returned in length, and this count does not include the null termination character. If the length of the returned string is not required, a value of NULL can be passed in the length argument.

The type argument will return a pointer to the attribute variable's data type. The symbolic constants GL_FLOAT, GL_FLOAT_VEC2, GL_FLOAT_VEC3, GL_FLOAT_VEC4, GL_FLOAT_MAT2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3, GL_FLOAT_MAT4, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x3, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT4x2, or GL_FLOAT_MAT4x3 may be returned. The size argument will return the size of the attribute, in units of the type returned in type.

The list of active attribute variables may include both built-in attribute variables (which begin with the prefix "gl_") as well as user-defined attribute variable names.

This function will return as much information as it can about the specified active attribute variable. If no information is available, length will be 0, and name will be an empty string. This situation could occur if this function is called after a link operation that failed. If an error occurs, the return values length, size, type, and name will be unmodified.

Notes

glGetActiveAttrib is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

GL_FLOAT_MAT2x3, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT4x2, and GL_FLOAT_MAT4x3 will only be returned as a type if the GL version is 2.1 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if index is greater than or equal to the number of active attribute variables in program.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetActiveAttrib is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if bufSize is less than 0.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS.

glGetProgram with argument GL_ACTIVE_ATTRIBUTES or GL_ACTIVE_ATTRIBUTE_MAX_LENGTH.

glIsProgram

See Also

glBindAttribLocation, glLinkProgram, glVertexAttrib, glVertexAttribPointer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetActiveUniform — Returns information about an active uniform variable for the specified program object

C Specification

void glGetActiveUniform( | GLuint   | program,
  | GLuint   | index,
  | GLsizei   | bufSize,
  | GLsizei *  | length,
  | GLint *  | size,
  | GLenum *  | type,
  | GLchar *  | name);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object to be queried.

index

Specifies the index of the uniform variable to be queried.

bufSize

Specifies the maximum number of characters OpenGL is allowed to write in the character buffer indicated by name.

length

Returns the number of characters actually written by OpenGL in the string indicated by name (excluding the null terminator) if a value other than NULL is passed.

size

Returns the size of the uniform variable.

type

Returns the data type of the uniform variable.

name

Returns a null terminated string containing the name of the uniform variable.

Description

glGetActiveUniform returns information about an active uniform variable in the program object specified by program. The number of active uniform variables can be obtained by calling glGetProgram with the value GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORMS. A value of 0 for index selects the first active uniform variable. Permissible values for index range from 0 to the number of active uniform variables minus 1.

Shaders may use either built-in uniform variables, user-defined uniform variables, or both. Built-in uniform variables have a prefix of "gl_" and reference existing OpenGL state or values derived from such state (e.g., gl_Fog, gl_ModelViewMatrix, etc., see the OpenGL Shading Language specification for a complete list.) User-defined uniform variables have arbitrary names and obtain their values from the application through calls to glUniform. A uniform variable (either built-in or user-defined) is considered active if it is determined during the link operation that it may be accessed during program execution. Therefore, program should have previously been the target of a call to glLinkProgram, but it is not necessary for it to have been linked successfully.

The size of the character buffer required to store the longest uniform variable name in program can be obtained by calling glGetProgram with the value GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORM_MAX_LENGTH. This value should be used to allocate a buffer of sufficient size to store the returned uniform variable name. The size of this character buffer is passed in bufSize, and a pointer to this character buffer is passed in name.

glGetActiveUniform returns the name of the uniform variable indicated by index, storing it in the character buffer specified by name. The string returned will be null terminated. The actual number of characters written into this buffer is returned in length, and this count does not include the null termination character. If the length of the returned string is not required, a value of NULL can be passed in the length argument.

The type argument will return a pointer to the uniform variable's data type. The symbolic constants GL_FLOAT, GL_FLOAT_VEC2, GL_FLOAT_VEC3, GL_FLOAT_VEC4, GL_INT, GL_INT_VEC2, GL_INT_VEC3, GL_INT_VEC4, GL_BOOL, GL_BOOL_VEC2, GL_BOOL_VEC3, GL_BOOL_VEC4, GL_FLOAT_MAT2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3, GL_FLOAT_MAT4, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x3, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT4x2, GL_FLOAT_MAT4x3, GL_SAMPLER_1D, GL_SAMPLER_2D, GL_SAMPLER_3D, GL_SAMPLER_CUBE, GL_SAMPLER_1D_SHADOW, or GL_SAMPLER_2D_SHADOW may be returned.

If one or more elements of an array are active, the name of the array is returned in name, the type is returned in type, and the size parameter returns the highest array element index used, plus one, as determined by the compiler and/or linker. Only one active uniform variable will be reported for a uniform array.

Uniform variables that are declared as structures or arrays of structures will not be returned directly by this function. Instead, each of these uniform variables will be reduced to its fundamental components containing the "." and "[]" operators such that each of the names is valid as an argument to glGetUniformLocation. Each of these reduced uniform variables is counted as one active uniform variable and is assigned an index. A valid name cannot be a structure, an array of structures, or a subcomponent of a vector or matrix.

The size of the uniform variable will be returned in size. Uniform variables other than arrays will have a size of 1. Structures and arrays of structures will be reduced as described earlier, such that each of the names returned will be a data type in the earlier list. If this reduction results in an array, the size returned will be as described for uniform arrays; otherwise, the size returned will be 1.

The list of active uniform variables may include both built-in uniform variables (which begin with the prefix "gl_") as well as user-defined uniform variable names.

This function will return as much information as it can about the specified active uniform variable. If no information is available, length will be 0, and name will be an empty string. This situation could occur if this function is called after a link operation that failed. If an error occurs, the return values length, size, type, and name will be unmodified.

Notes

glGetActiveUniform is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

GL_FLOAT_MAT2x3, GL_FLOAT_MAT2x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x2, GL_FLOAT_MAT3x4, GL_FLOAT_MAT4x2, and GL_FLOAT_MAT4x3 will only be returned as a type if the GL version is 2.1 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if index is greater than or equal to the number of active uniform variables in program.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetActiveUniform is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if bufSize is less than 0.

Associated Gets

glGet with argument GL_MAX_VERTEX_UNIFORM_COMPONENTS or GL_MAX_FRAGMENT_UNIFORM_COMPONENTS.

glGetProgram with argument GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORMS or GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORM_MAX_LENGTH.

glIsProgram

See Also

glGetUniform, glGetUniformLocation, glLinkProgram, glUniform, glUseProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetAttribLocation — Returns the location of an attribute variable

C Specification

GLint glGetAttribLocation( | GLuint   | program,
  | const GLchar *  | name);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object to be queried.

name

Points to a null terminated string containing the name of the attribute variable whose location is to be queried.

Description

glGetAttribLocation queries the previously linked program object specified by program for the attribute variable specified by name and returns the index of the generic vertex attribute that is bound to that attribute variable. If name is a matrix attribute variable, the index of the first column of the matrix is returned. If the named attribute variable is not an active attribute in the specified program object or if name starts with the reserved prefix "gl_", a value of -1 is returned.

The association between an attribute variable name and a generic attribute index can be specified at any time by calling glBindAttribLocation. Attribute bindings do not go into effect until glLinkProgram is called. After a program object has been linked successfully, the index values for attribute variables remain fixed until the next link command occurs. The attribute values can only be queried after a link if the link was successful. glGetAttribLocation returns the binding that actually went into effect the last time glLinkProgram was called for the specified program object. Attribute bindings that have been specified since the last link operation are not returned by glGetAttribLocation.

Notes

glGetAttribLocation is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program has not been successfully linked.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetAttribLocation is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetActiveAttrib with argument program and the index of an active attribute

glIsProgram

See Also

glBindAttribLocation, glLinkProgram, glVertexAttrib, glVertexAttribPointer

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetProgramInfoLog — Returns the information log for a program object

C Specification

void glGetProgramInfoLog( | GLuint   | program,
  | GLsizei   | maxLength,
  | GLsizei *  | length,
  | GLchar *  | infoLog);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object whose information log is to be queried.

maxLength

Specifies the size of the character buffer for storing the returned information log.

length

Returns the length of the string returned in infoLog (excluding the null terminator).

infoLog

Specifies an array of characters that is used to return the information log.

Description

glGetProgramInfoLog returns the information log for the specified program object. The information log for a program object is modified when the program object is linked or validated. The string that is returned will be null terminated.

glGetProgramInfoLog returns in infoLog as much of the information log as it can, up to a maximum of maxLength characters. The number of characters actually returned, excluding the null termination character, is specified by length. If the length of the returned string is not required, a value of NULL can be passed in the length argument. The size of the buffer required to store the returned information log can be obtained by calling glGetProgram with the value GL_INFO_LOG_LENGTH.

The information log for a program object is either an empty string, or a string containing information about the last link operation, or a string containing information about the last validation operation. It may contain diagnostic messages, warning messages, and other information. When a program object is created, its information log will be a string of length 0.

Notes

glGetProgramInfoLog is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

The information log for a program object is the OpenGL implementer's primary mechanism for conveying information about linking and validating. Therefore, the information log can be helpful to application developers during the development process, even when these operations are successful. Application developers should not expect different OpenGL implementations to produce identical information logs.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if maxLength is less than 0.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetProgramInfoLog is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetProgram with argument GL_INFO_LOG_LENGTH

glIsProgram

See Also

glCompileShader, glGetShaderInfoLog, glLinkProgram, glValidateProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glGetString — return a string describing the current GL connection

C Specification

const GLubyte* glGetString( | GLenum   | name);

Parameters

name

Specifies a symbolic constant, one of GL_VENDOR, GL_RENDERER, GL_VERSION, GL_SHADING_LANGUAGE_VERSION, or GL_EXTENSIONS.

Description

glGetString returns a pointer to a static string describing some aspect of the current GL connection. name can be one of the following:

GL_VENDOR

Returns the company responsible for this GL implementation. This name does not change from release to release.

GL_RENDERER

Returns the name of the renderer. This name is typically specific to a particular configuration of a hardware platform. It does not change from release to release.

GL_VERSION

Returns a version or release number.

GL_SHADING_LANGUAGE_VERSION

Returns a version or release number for the shading language.

GL_EXTENSIONS

Returns a space-separated list of supported extensions to GL.

Because the GL does not include queries for the performance characteristics of an implementation, some applications are written to recognize known platforms and modify their GL usage based on known performance characteristics of these platforms. Strings GL_VENDOR and GL_RENDERER together uniquely specify a platform. They do not change from release to release and should be used by platform-recognition algorithms.

Some applications want to make use of features that are not part of the standard GL. These features may be implemented as extensions to the standard GL. The GL_EXTENSIONS string is a space-separated list of supported GL extensions. (Extension names never contain a space character.)

The GL_VERSION and GL_SHADING_LANGUAGE_VERSION strings begin with a version number. The version number uses one of these forms:

major_number.minor_number major_number.minor_number.release_number

Vendor-specific information may follow the version number. Its format depends on the implementation, but a space always separates the version number and the vendor-specific information.

All strings are null-terminated.

Notes

If an error is generated, glGetString returns 0.

The client and server may support different versions or extensions. glGetString always returns a compatible version number or list of extensions. The release number always describes the server.

GL_SHADING_LANGUAGE_VERSION is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if name is not an accepted value.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetString is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glGetUniformLocation — Returns the location of a uniform variable

C Specification

GLint glGetUniformLocation( | GLuint   | program,
  | const GLchar *  | name);

Parameters

program

Specifies the program object to be queried.

name

Points to a null terminated string containing the name of the uniform variable whose location is to be queried.

Description

glGetUniformLocation returns an integer that represents the location of a specific uniform variable within a program object. name must be a null terminated string that contains no white space. name must be an active uniform variable name in program that is not a structure, an array of structures, or a subcomponent of a vector or a matrix. This function returns -1 if name does not correspond to an active uniform variable in program or if name starts with the reserved prefix "gl_".

Uniform variables that are structures or arrays of structures may be queried by calling glGetUniformLocation for each field within the structure. The array element operator "[]" and the structure field operator "." may be used in name in order to select elements within an array or fields within a structure. The result of using these operators is not allowed to be another structure, an array of structures, or a subcomponent of a vector or a matrix. Except if the last part of name indicates a uniform variable array, the location of the first element of an array can be retrieved by using the name of the array, or by using the name appended by "[0]".

The actual locations assigned to uniform variables are not known until the program object is linked successfully. After linking has occurred, the command glGetUniformLocation can be used to obtain the location of a uniform variable. This location value can then be passed to glUniform to set the value of the uniform variable or to glGetUniform in order to query the current value of the uniform variable. After a program object has been linked successfully, the index values for uniform variables remain fixed until the next link command occurs. Uniform variable locations and values can only be queried after a link if the link was successful.

Notes

glGetUniformLocation is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program has not been successfully linked.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glGetUniformLocation is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetActiveUniform with arguments program and the index of an active uniform variable

glGetProgram with arguments program and GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORMS or GL_ACTIVE_UNIFORM_MAX_LENGTH

glGetUniform with arguments program and the name of a uniform variable

glIsProgram

See Also

glLinkProgram, glUniform

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glLinkProgram — Links a program object

C Specification

void glLinkProgram( | GLuint   | program);

Parameters

program

Specifies the handle of the program object to be linked.

Description

glLinkProgram links the program object specified by program. If any shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER are attached to program, they will be used to create an executable that will run on the programmable vertex processor. If any shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER are attached to program, they will be used to create an executable that will run on the programmable fragment processor.

The status of the link operation will be stored as part of the program object's state. This value will be set to GL_TRUE if the program object was linked without errors and is ready for use, and GL_FALSE otherwise. It can be queried by calling glGetProgram with arguments program and GL_LINK_STATUS.

As a result of a successful link operation, all active user-defined uniform variables belonging to program will be initialized to 0, and each of the program object's active uniform variables will be assigned a location that can be queried by calling glGetUniformLocation. Also, any active user-defined attribute variables that have not been bound to a generic vertex attribute index will be bound to one at this time.

Linking of a program object can fail for a number of reasons as specified in the OpenGL Shading Language Specification. The following lists some of the conditions that will cause a link error.

The number of active attribute variables supported by the implementation has been exceeded.

The storage limit for uniform variables has been exceeded.

The number of active uniform variables supported by the implementation has been exceeded.

The main function is missing for the vertex shader or the fragment shader.

A varying variable actually used in the fragment shader is not declared in the same way (or is not declared at all) in the vertex shader.

A reference to a function or variable name is unresolved.

A shared global is declared with two different types or two different initial values.

One or more of the attached shader objects has not been successfully compiled.

Binding a generic attribute matrix caused some rows of the matrix to fall outside the allowed maximum of GL_MAX_VERTEX_ATTRIBS.

Not enough contiguous vertex attribute slots could be found to bind attribute matrices.

When a program object has been successfully linked, the program object can be made part of current state by calling glUseProgram. Whether or not the link operation was successful, the program object's information log will be overwritten. The information log can be retrieved by calling glGetProgramInfoLog.

glLinkProgram will also install the generated executables as part of the current rendering state if the link operation was successful and the specified program object is already currently in use as a result of a previous call to glUseProgram. If the program object currently in use is relinked unsuccessfully, its link status will be set to GL_FALSE , but the executables and associated state will remain part of the current state until a subsequent call to glUseProgram removes it from use. After it is removed from use, it cannot be made part of current state until it has been successfully relinked.

If program contains shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER but does not contain shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER, the vertex shader will be linked against the implicit interface for fixed functionality fragment processing. Similarly, if program contains shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER but it does not contain shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER, the fragment shader will be linked against the implicit interface for fixed functionality vertex processing.

The program object's information log is updated and the program is generated at the time of the link operation. After the link operation, applications are free to modify attached shader objects, compile attached shader objects, detach shader objects, delete shader objects, and attach additional shader objects. None of these operations affects the information log or the program that is part of the program object.

Notes

glLinkProgram is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

If the link operation is unsuccessful, any information about a previous link operation on program is lost (i.e., a failed link does not restore the old state of program ). Certain information can still be retrieved from program even after an unsuccessful link operation. See for instance glGetActiveAttrib and glGetActiveUniform.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is not a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glLinkProgram is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with the argument GL_CURRENT_PROGRAM

glGetActiveAttrib with argument program and the index of an active attribute variable

glGetActiveUniform with argument program and the index of an active uniform variable

glGetAttachedShaders with argument program

glGetAttribLocation with argument program and an attribute variable name

glGetProgram with arguments program and GL_LINK_STATUS

glGetProgramInfoLog with argument program

glGetUniform with argument program and a uniform variable location

glGetUniformLocation with argument program and a uniform variable name

glIsProgram

See Also

glAttachShader, glBindAttribLocation, glCompileShader, glCreateProgram, glDeleteProgram, glDetachShader, glUniform, glUseProgram, glValidateProgram

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glMapBuffer — map a buffer object's data store

C Specification

void * glMapBuffer( | GLenum   | target,
  | GLenum   | access);

Parameters

target

Specifies the target buffer object being mapped. The symbolic constant must be GL_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_ELEMENT_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_PIXEL_PACK_BUFFER, or GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER.

access

Specifies the access policy, indicating whether it will be possible to read from, write to, or both read from and write to the buffer object's mapped data store. The symbolic constant must be GL_READ_ONLY, GL_WRITE_ONLY, or GL_READ_WRITE.

C Specification

GLboolean glUnmapBuffer( | GLenum   | target);

Parameters

target

Specifies the target buffer object being unmapped. The symbolic constant must be GL_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_ELEMENT_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_PIXEL_PACK_BUFFER, or GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER.

Description

glMapBuffer maps to the client's address space the entire data store of the buffer object currently bound to target. The data can then be directly read and/or written relative to the returned pointer, depending on the specified access policy. If the GL is unable to map the buffer object's data store, glMapBuffer generates an error and returns NULL. This may occur for system-specific reasons, such as low virtual memory availability.

If a mapped data store is accessed in a way inconsistent with the specified access policy, no error is generated, but performance may be negatively impacted and system errors, including program termination, may result. Unlike the usage parameter of glBufferData, access is not a hint, and does in fact constrain the usage of the mapped data store on some GL implementations. In order to achieve the highest performance available, a buffer object's data store should be used in ways consistent with both its specified usage and access parameters.

A mapped data store must be unmapped with glUnmapBuffer before its buffer object is used. Otherwise an error will be generated by any GL command that attempts to dereference the buffer object's data store. When a data store is unmapped, the pointer to its data store becomes invalid. glUnmapBuffer returns GL_TRUE unless the data store contents have become corrupt during the time the data store was mapped. This can occur for system-specific reasons that affect the availability of graphics memory, such as screen mode changes. In such situations, GL_FALSE is returned and the data store contents are undefined. An application must detect this rare condition and reinitialize the data store.

A buffer object's mapped data store is automatically unmapped when the buffer object is deleted or its data store is recreated with glBufferData.

Notes

If an error is generated, glMapBuffer returns NULL, and glUnmapBuffer returns GL_FALSE.

glMapBuffer and glUnmapBuffer are available only if the GL version is 1.5 or greater.

GL_PIXEL_PACK_BUFFER and GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER are available only if the GL version is 2.1 or greater.

Parameter values passed to GL commands may not be sourced from the returned pointer. No error will be generated, but results will be undefined and will likely vary across GL implementations.

Errors

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if target is not GL_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_ELEMENT_ARRAY_BUFFER, GL_PIXEL_PACK_BUFFER, or GL_PIXEL_UNPACK_BUFFER.

GL_INVALID_ENUM is generated if access is not GL_READ_ONLY, GL_WRITE_ONLY, or GL_READ_WRITE.

GL_OUT_OF_MEMORY is generated when glMapBuffer is executed if the GL is unable to map the buffer object's data store. This may occur for a variety of system-specific reasons, such as the absence of sufficient remaining virtual memory.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if the reserved buffer object name 0 is bound to target.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glMapBuffer is executed for a buffer object whose data store is already mapped.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glUnmapBuffer is executed for a buffer object whose data store is not currently mapped.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glMapBuffer or glUnmapBuffer is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGetBufferPointerv with argument GL_BUFFER_MAP_POINTER

glGetBufferParameteriv with argument GL_BUFFER_MAPPED, GL_BUFFER_ACCESS, or GL_BUFFER_USAGE

See Also

glBindBuffer, glBufferData, glBufferSubData, glDeleteBuffers

Copyright

Copyright © 2005 Addison-Wesley. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

gluBeginTrim — delimit a NURBS trimming loop definition

C Specification

void gluBeginTrim( | GLUnurbs*   | nurb);

C Specification

void gluEndTrim( | GLUnurbs*   | nurb);

Parameters

nurb

Specifies the NURBS object (created with gluNewNurbsRenderer).

Description

Use gluBeginTrim to mark the beginning of a trimming loop and gluEndTrim to mark the end of a trimming loop. A trimming loop is a set of oriented curve segments (forming a closed curve) that define boundaries of a NURBS surface. You include these trimming loops in the definition of a NURBS surface, between calls to gluBeginSurface and gluEndSurface.

The definition for a NURBS surface can contain many trimming loops. For example, if you wrote a definition for a NURBS surface that resembled a rectangle with a hole punched out, the definition would contain two trimming loops. One loop would define the outer edge of the rectangle; the other would define the hole punched out of the rectangle. The definitions of each of these trimming loops would be bracketed by a gluBeginTrim/gluEndTrim pair.

The definition of a single closed trimming loop can consist of multiple curve segments, each described as a piecewise linear curve (see gluPwlCurve) or as a single NURBS curve (see gluNurbsCurve), or as a combination of both in any order. The only library calls that can appear in a trimming loop definition (between the calls to gluBeginTrim and gluEndTrim) are gluPwlCurve and gluNurbsCurve.

The area of the NURBS surface that is displayed is the region in the domain to the left of the trimming curve as the curve parameter increases. Thus, the retained region of the NURBS surface is inside a counterclockwise trimming loop and outside a clockwise trimming loop. For the rectangle mentioned earlier, the trimming loop for the outer edge of the rectangle runs counterclockwise, while the trimming loop for the punched-out hole runs clockwise.

If you use more than one curve to define a single trimming loop, the curve segments must form a closed loop (that is, the endpoint of each curve must be the starting point of the next curve, and the endpoint of the final curve must be the starting point of the first curve). If the endpoints of the curve are sufficiently close together but not exactly coincident, they will be coerced to match. If the endpoints are not sufficiently close, an error results (see gluNurbsCallback).

If a trimming loop definition contains multiple curves, the direction of the curves must be consistent (that is, the inside must be to the left of all of the curves). Nested trimming loops are legal as long as the curve orientations alternate correctly. If trimming curves are self-intersecting, or intersect one another, an error results.

If no trimming information is given for a NURBS surface, the entire surface is drawn.

Example

This code fragment defines a trimming loop that consists of one piecewise linear curve, and two NURBS curves:

gluBeginTrim(nobj);
   gluPwlCurve(..., GLU_MAP1_TRIM_2);
   gluNurbsCurve(..., GLU_MAP1_TRIM_2);
   gluNurbsCurve(..., GLU_MAP1_TRIM_3);
gluEndTrim(nobj);
            

See Also

gluBeginSurface, gluNewNurbsRenderer, gluNurbsCallback, gluNurbsCurve, gluPwlCurve

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

gluNurbsCallback — define a callback for a NURBS object

C Specification

void gluNurbsCallback( | GLUnurbs*   | nurb,
  | GLenum   | which,
  | _GLUfuncptr   | CallBackFunc);

Parameters

nurb

Specifies the NURBS object (created with gluNewNurbsRenderer).

which

Specifies the callback being defined. Valid values are GLU_NURBS_BEGIN, GLU_NURBS_VERTEX, GLU_NURBS_NORMAL, GLU_NURBS_COLOR, GLU_NURBS_TEXTURE_COORD, GLU_NURBS_END, GLU_NURBS_BEGIN_DATA, GLU_NURBS_VERTEX_DATA, GLU_NURBS_NORMAL_DATA, GLU_NURBS_COLOR_DATA, GLU_NURBS_TEXTURE_COORD_DATA, GLU_NURBS_END_DATA, and GLU_NURBS_ERROR.

CallBackFunc

Specifies the function that the callback calls.

Description

gluNurbsCallback is used to define a callback to be used by a NURBS object. If the specified callback is already defined, then it is replaced. If CallBackFunc is NULL, then this callback will not get invoked and the related data, if any, will be lost.

Except the error callback, these callbacks are used by NURBS tessellator (when GLU_NURBS_MODE is set to be GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR) to return back the OpenGL polygon primitives resulting from the tessellation. Note that there are two versions of each callback: one with a user data pointer and one without. If both versions for a particular callback are specified then the callback with the user data pointer will be used. Note that ``userData'' is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData.

The error callback function is effective no matter which value that GLU_NURBS_MODE is set to. All other callback functions are effective only when GLU_NURBS_MODE is set to GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR.

The legal callbacks are as follows:

GLU_NURBS_BEGIN

The begin callback indicates the start of a primitive. The function takes a single argument of type GLenum, which can be one of GLU_LINES, GLU_LINE_STRIP, GLU_TRIANGLE_FAN, GLU_TRIANGLE_STRIP, GLU_TRIANGLES, or GLU_QUAD_STRIP. The default begin callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback looks like:

void begin( GLenum type );
                        

GLU_NURBS_BEGIN_DATA

The same as the GLU_NURBS_BEGIN callback except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void beginData(GLenum type, void *userData);
                        

GLU_NURBS_VERTEX

The vertex callback indicates a vertex of the primitive. The coordinates of the vertex are stored in the parameter ``vertex''. All the generated vertices have dimension 3; that is, homogeneous coordinates have been transformed into affine coordinates. The default vertex callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void vertex( GLfloat *vertex );
                        

GLU_NURBS_VERTEX_DATA

This is the same as the GLU_NURBS_VERTEX callback, except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void vertexData( GLfloat *vertex, void *userData );
                        

GLU_NURBS_NORMAL

The normal callback is invoked as the vertex normal is generated. The components of the normal are stored in the parameter ``normal.'' In the case of a NURBS curve, the callback function is effective only when the user provides a normal map (GLU_MAP1_NORMAL). In the case of a NURBS surface, if a normal map (GLU_MAP2_NORMAL) is provided, then the generated normal is computed from the normal map. If a normal map is not provided, then a surface normal is computed in a manner similar to that described for evaluators when GLU_AUTO_NORMAL is enabled. The default normal callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void normal( GLfloat *normal );
                        

GLU_NURBS_NORMAL_DATA

The same as the GLU_NURBS_NORMAL callback except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void normalData( GLfloat *normal, void *userData );
                        

GLU_NURBS_COLOR

The color callback is invoked as the color of a vertex is generated. The components of the color are stored in the parameter ``color.'' This callback is effective only when the user provides a color map (GLU_MAP1_COLOR_4 or GLU_MAP2_COLOR_4). ``color'' contains four components: R, G, B, A. The default color callback function is NULL. The prototype for this callback function looks like:

void color( GLfloat *color );
                        

GLU_NURBS_COLOR_DATA

The same as the GLU_NURBS_COLOR callback except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void colorData( GLfloat *color, void *userData );
                        

GLU_NURBS_TEXTURE_COORD

The texture callback is invoked as the texture coordinates of a vertex are generated. These coordinates are stored in the parameter ``texCoord.'' The number of texture coordinates can be 1, 2, 3, or 4 depending on which type of texture map is specified (GLU_MAP1_TEXTURE_COORD_1, GLU_MAP1_TEXTURE_COORD_2, GLU_MAP1_TEXTURE_COORD_3, GLU_MAP1_TEXTURE_COORD_4, GLU_MAP2_TEXTURE_COORD_1, GLU_MAP2_TEXTURE_COORD_2, GLU_MAP2_TEXTURE_COORD_3, GLU_MAP2_TEXTURE_COORD_4). If no texture map is specified, this callback function will not be called. The default texture callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void texCoord( GLfloat *texCoord );
                        

GLU_NURBS_TEXTURE_COORD_DATA

This is the same as the GLU_NURBS_TEXTURE_COORD callback, except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void texCoordData( GLfloat *texCoord, void *userData );
                        

GLU_NURBS_END

The end callback is invoked at the end of a primitive. The default end callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void end( void );
                        

GLU_NURBS_END_DATA

This is the same as the GLU_NURBS_END callback, except that it takes an additional pointer argument. This pointer is a copy of the pointer that was specified at the last call to gluNurbsCallbackData. The default callback function is NULL. The function prototype for this callback function looks like:

void endData( void  *userData );
                        

GLU_NURBS_ERROR

The error function is called when an error is encountered. Its single argument is of type GLenum, and it indicates the specific error that occurred. There are 37 errors unique to NURBS, named GLU_NURBS_ERROR1 through GLU_NURBS_ERROR37. Character strings describing these errors can be retrieved with gluErrorString.

Notes

gluNurbsCallback is available only if the GLU version is 1.2 or greater.

GLU version 1.2 supports only the GLU_ERROR parameter for which. The GLU_ERROR value is deprecated in GLU version 1.3 in favor of GLU_NURBS_ERROR. All other accepted values for CallBackFunc are available only if the GLU version is 1.3 or greater.

See Also

gluErrorString, gluNewNurbsRenderer, gluNurbsCallbackData, gluNurbsProperty

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

gluNurbsProperty — set a NURBS property

C Specification

void gluNurbsProperty( | GLUnurbs*   | nurb,
  | GLenum   | property,
  | GLfloat   | value);

Parameters

nurb

Specifies the NURBS object (created with gluNewNurbsRenderer).

property

Specifies the property to be set. Valid values are GLU_SAMPLING_TOLERANCE, GLU_DISPLAY_MODE, GLU_CULLING, GLU_AUTO_LOAD_MATRIX, GLU_PARAMETRIC_TOLERANCE, GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD, GLU_U_STEP, GLU_V_STEP, or GLU_NURBS_MODE.

value

Specifies the value of the indicated property. It may be a numeric value or one of GLU_OUTLINE_POLYGON, GLU_FILL, GLU_OUTLINE_PATCH, GLU_TRUE, GLU_FALSE, GLU_PATH_LENGTH, GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR, GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE, GLU_NURBS_RENDERER, or GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR.

Description

gluNurbsProperty is used to control properties stored in a NURBS object. These properties affect the way that a NURBS curve is rendered. The accepted values for property are as follows:

GLU_NURBS_MODE

value should be set to be either GLU_NURBS_RENDERER or GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR. When set to GLU_NURBS_RENDERER, NURBS objects are tessellated into OpenGL primitives and sent to the pipeline for rendering. When set to GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR, NURBS objects are tessellated into OpenGL primitives but the vertices, normals, colors, and/or textures are retrieved back through a callback interface (see gluNurbsCallback). This allows the user to cache the tessellated results for further processing. The initial value is GLU_NURBS_RENDERER.

GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD

Specifies how a NURBS surface should be tessellated. value may be one of GLU_PATH_LENGTH, GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR, GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE, GLU_OBJECT_PATH_LENGTH, or GLU_OBJECT_PARAMETRIC_ERROR. When set to GLU_PATH_LENGTH, the surface is rendered so that the maximum length, in pixels, of the edges of the tessellation polygons is no greater than what is specified by GLU_SAMPLING_TOLERANCE.

GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR specifies that the surface is rendered in such a way that the value specified by GLU_PARAMETRIC_TOLERANCE describes the maximum distance, in pixels, between the tessellation polygons and the surfaces they approximate.

GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE allows users to specify, in parametric coordinates, how many sample points per unit length are taken in u, v direction.

GLU_OBJECT_PATH_LENGTH is similar to GLU_PATH_LENGTH except that it is view independent; that is, the surface is rendered so that the maximum length, in object space, of edges of the tessellation polygons is no greater than what is specified by GLU_SAMPLING_TOLERANCE.

GLU_OBJECT_PARAMETRIC_ERROR is similar to GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR except that it is view independent; that is, the surface is rendered in such a way that the value specified by GLU_PARAMETRIC_TOLERANCE describes the maximum distance, in object space, between the tessellation polygons and the surfaces they approximate.

The initial value of GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD is GLU_PATH_LENGTH.

GLU_SAMPLING_TOLERANCE

Specifies the maximum length, in pixels or in object space length unit, to use when the sampling method is set to GLU_PATH_LENGTH or GLU_OBJECT_PATH_LENGTH. The NURBS code is conservative when rendering a curve or surface, so the actual length can be somewhat shorter. The initial value is 50.0 pixels.

GLU_PARAMETRIC_TOLERANCE

Specifies the maximum distance, in pixels or in object space length unit, to use when the sampling method is GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR or GLU_OBJECT_PARAMETRIC_ERROR. The initial value is 0.5.

GLU_U_STEP

Specifies the number of sample points per unit length taken along the u axis in parametric coordinates. It is needed when GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD is set to GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE. The initial value is 100.

GLU_V_STEP

Specifies the number of sample points per unit length taken along the v axis in parametric coordinate. It is needed when GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD is set to GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE. The initial value is 100.

GLU_DISPLAY_MODE

value can be set to GLU_OUTLINE_POLYGON, GLU_FILL, or GLU_OUTLINE_PATCH. When GLU_NURBS_MODE is set to be GLU_NURBS_RENDERER, value defines how a NURBS surface should be rendered. When value is set to GLU_FILL, the surface is rendered as a set of polygons. When value is set to GLU_OUTLINE_POLYGON, the NURBS library draws only the outlines of the polygons created by tessellation. When value is set to GLU_OUTLINE_PATCH just the outlines of patches and trim curves defined by the user are drawn.

When GLU_NURBS_MODE is set to be GLU_NURBS_TESSELLATOR, value defines how a NURBS surface should be tessellated. When GLU_DISPLAY_MODE is set to GLU_FILL or GLU_OUTLINE_POLYGON, the NURBS surface is tessellated into OpenGL triangle primitives that can be retrieved back through callback functions. If GLU_DISPLAY_MODE is set to GLU_OUTLINE_PATCH, only the outlines of the patches and trim curves are generated as a sequence of line strips that can be retrieved back through callback functions.

The initial value is GLU_FILL.

GLU_CULLING

value is a boolean value that, when set to GLU_TRUE, indicates that a NURBS curve should be discarded prior to tessellation if its control points lie outside the current viewport. The initial value is GLU_FALSE.

GLU_AUTO_LOAD_MATRIX

value is a boolean value. When set to GLU_TRUE, the NURBS code downloads the projection matrix, the modelview matrix, and the viewport from the GL server to compute sampling and culling matrices for each NURBS curve that is rendered. Sampling and culling matrices are required to determine the tessellation of a NURBS surface into line segments or polygons and to cull a NURBS surface if it lies outside the viewport.

If this mode is set to GLU_FALSE, then the program needs to provide a projection matrix, a modelview matrix, and a viewport for the NURBS renderer to use to construct sampling and culling matrices. This can be done with the gluLoadSamplingMatrices function. This mode is initially set to GLU_TRUE. Changing it from GLU_TRUE to GLU_FALSE does not affect the sampling and culling matrices until gluLoadSamplingMatrices is called.

Notes

If GLU_AUTO_LOAD_MATRIX is true, sampling and culling may be executed incorrectly if NURBS routines are compiled into a display list.

A property of GLU_PARAMETRIC_TOLERANCE, GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD, GLU_U_STEP, or GLU_V_STEP, or a value of GLU_PATH_LENGTH, GLU_PARAMETRIC_ERROR, GLU_DOMAIN_DISTANCE are only available if the GLU version is 1.1 or greater. They are not valid parameters in GLU 1.0.

gluGetString can be used to determine the GLU version.

GLU_NURBS_MODE is only available if the GLU version is 1.3 or greater.

The GLU_OBJECT_PATH_LENGTH and GLU_OBJECT_PARAMETRIC_ERROR values for the GLU_SAMPLING_METHOD property are only available if the GLU version is 1.3 or greater.

See Also

gluGetNurbsProperty, gluGetString, gluLoadSamplingMatrices, gluNewNurbsRenderer, gluNurbsCallback

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glUseProgram — Installs a program object as part of current rendering state

C Specification

void glUseProgram( | GLuint   | program);

Parameters

program

Specifies the handle of the program object whose executables are to be used as part of current rendering state.

Description

glUseProgram installs the program object specified by program as part of current rendering state. One or more executables are created in a program object by successfully attaching shader objects to it with glAttachShader, successfully compiling the shader objects with glCompileShader, and successfully linking the program object with glLinkProgram.

A program object will contain an executable that will run on the vertex processor if it contains one or more shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER that have been successfully compiled and linked. Similarly, a program object will contain an executable that will run on the fragment processor if it contains one or more shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER that have been successfully compiled and linked.

Successfully installing an executable on a programmable processor will cause the corresponding fixed functionality of OpenGL to be disabled. Specifically, if an executable is installed on the vertex processor, the OpenGL fixed functionality will be disabled as follows.

The modelview matrix is not applied to vertex coordinates.

The projection matrix is not applied to vertex coordinates.

The texture matrices are not applied to texture coordinates.

Normals are not transformed to eye coordinates.

Normals are not rescaled or normalized.

Normalization of GL_AUTO_NORMAL evaluated normals is not performed.

Texture coordinates are not generated automatically.

Per-vertex lighting is not performed.

Color material computations are not performed.

Color index lighting is not performed.

This list also applies when setting the current raster position.

The executable that is installed on the vertex processor is expected to implement any or all of the desired functionality from the preceding list. Similarly, if an executable is installed on the fragment processor, the OpenGL fixed functionality will be disabled as follows.

Texture environment and texture functions are not applied.

Texture application is not applied.

Color sum is not applied.

Fog is not applied.

Again, the fragment shader that is installed is expected to implement any or all of the desired functionality from the preceding list.

While a program object is in use, applications are free to modify attached shader objects, compile attached shader objects, attach additional shader objects, and detach or delete shader objects. None of these operations will affect the executables that are part of the current state. However, relinking the program object that is currently in use will install the program object as part of the current rendering state if the link operation was successful (see glLinkProgram ). If the program object currently in use is relinked unsuccessfully, its link status will be set to GL_FALSE, but the executables and associated state will remain part of the current state until a subsequent call to glUseProgram removes it from use. After it is removed from use, it cannot be made part of current state until it has been successfully relinked.

If program contains shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER but it does not contain shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER, an executable will be installed on the vertex processor, but fixed functionality will be used for fragment processing. Similarly, if program contains shader objects of type GL_FRAGMENT_SHADER but it does not contain shader objects of type GL_VERTEX_SHADER, an executable will be installed on the fragment processor, but fixed functionality will be used for vertex processing. If program is 0, the programmable processors will be disabled, and fixed functionality will be used for both vertex and fragment processing.

Notes

glUseProgram is available only if the GL version is 2.0 or greater.

While a program object is in use, the state that controls the disabled fixed functionality may also be updated using the normal OpenGL calls.

Like display lists and texture objects, the name space for program objects may be shared across a set of contexts, as long as the server sides of the contexts share the same address space. If the name space is shared across contexts, any attached objects and the data associated with those attached objects are shared as well.

Applications are responsible for providing the synchronization across API calls when objects are accessed from different execution threads.

Errors

GL_INVALID_VALUE is generated if program is neither 0 nor a value generated by OpenGL.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program is not a program object.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if program could not be made part of current state.

GL_INVALID_OPERATION is generated if glUseProgram is executed between the execution of glBegin and the corresponding execution of glEnd.

Associated Gets

glGet with the argument GL_CURRENT_PROGRAM

glGetActiveAttrib with a valid program object and the index of an active attribute variable

glGetActiveUniform with a valid program object and the index of an active uniform variable

glGetAttachedShaders with a valid program object

glGetAttribLocation with a valid program object and the name of an attribute variable

glGetProgram with a valid program object and the parameter to be queried

glGetProgramInfoLog with a valid program object

glGetUniform with a valid program object and the location of a uniform variable

glGetUniformLocation with a valid program object and the name of a uniform variable

glIsProgram

See Also

gllAttachShader, glBindAttribLocation, glCompileShader, glCreateProgram, glDeleteProgram, glDetachShader, glLinkProgram, glUniform, glValidateProgram, glVertexAttrib

Copyright

Copyright © 2003-2005 3Dlabs Inc. Ltd. This material may be distributed subject to the terms and conditions set forth in the Open Publication License, v 1.0, 8 June 1999. http://opencontent.org/openpub/.

Name

glXChooseFBConfig — return a list of GLX frame buffer configurations that match the specified attributes

C Specification

GLXFBConfig * glXChooseFBConfig( | Display *   | dpy,
  | int   | screen,
  | const int *   | attrib_list,
  | int *   | nelements);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

screen

Specifies the screen number.

attrib_list

Specifies a list of attribute/value pairs. The last attribute must be None.

nelements

Returns the number of elements in the list returned by glXChooseFBConfig.

Description

glXChooseFBConfig returns GLX frame buffer configurations that match the attributes specified in attrib_list, or NULL if no matches are found. If attrib_list is NULL, then glXChooseFBConfig returns an array of GLX frame buffer configurations that are available on the specified screen. If an error occurs, no frame buffer configurations exist on the specified screen, or if no frame buffer configurations match the specified attributes, then NULL is returned. Use XFree to free the memory returned by glXChooseFBConfig.

All attributes in attrib_list, including boolean attributes, are immediately followed by the corresponding desired value. The list is terminated with None. If an attribute is not specified in attrib_list, then the default value (see below) is used (and the attribute is said to be specified implicitly). For example, if GLX_STEREO is not specified, then it is assumed to be False. For some attributes, the default is GLX_DONT_CARE, meaning that any value is OK for this attribute, so the attribute will not be checked.

Attributes are matched in an attribute-specific manner. Some of the attributes, such as GLX_LEVEL, must match the specified value exactly; others, such as, GLX_RED_SIZE must meet or exceed the specified minimum values. If more than one GLX frame buffer configuration is found, then a list of configurations, sorted according to the ``best'' match criteria, is returned. The match criteria for each attribute and the exact sorting order is defined below.

The interpretations of the various GLX visual attributes are as follows:

GLX_FBCONFIG_ID

Must be followed by a valid XID that indicates the desired GLX frame buffer configuration. When a GLX_FBCONFIG_ID is specified, all attributes are ignored. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE.

GLX_BUFFER_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired color index buffer size. The smallest index buffer of at least the specified size is preferred. This attribute is ignored if GLX_COLOR_INDEX_BIT is not set in GLX_RENDER_TYPE. The default value is 0.

GLX_LEVEL

Must be followed by an integer buffer-level specification. This specification is honored exactly. Buffer level 0 corresponds to the default frame buffer of the display. Buffer level 1 is the first overlay frame buffer, level two the second overlay frame buffer, and so on. Negative buffer levels correspond to underlay frame buffers. The default value is 0.

GLX_DOUBLEBUFFER

Must be followed by True or False. If True is specified, then only double-buffered frame buffer configurations are considered; if False is specified, then only single-buffered frame buffer configurations are considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE.

GLX_STEREO

Must be followed by True or False. If True is specified, then only stereo frame buffer configurations are considered; if False is specified, then only monoscopic frame buffer configurations are considered. The default value is False.

GLX_AUX_BUFFERS

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired number of auxiliary buffers. Configurations with the smallest number of auxiliary buffers that meet or exceed the specified number are preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_RED_SIZE, GLX_GREEN_SIZE, GLX_BLUE_SIZE, GLX_ALPHA_SIZE

Each attribute, if present, must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification or GLX_DONT_CARE. The largest available total RGBA color buffer size (sum of GLX_RED_SIZE, GLX_GREEN_SIZE, GLX_BLUE_SIZE, and GLX_ALPHA_SIZE) of at least the minimum size specified for each color component is preferred. If the requested number of bits for a color component is 0 or GLX_DONT_CARE, it is not considered. The default value for each color component is 0.

GLX_DEPTH_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no depth buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest available depth buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_STENCIL_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired number of stencil bitplanes. The smallest stencil buffer of at least the specified size is preferred. If the desired value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no stencil buffer are preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_ACCUM_RED_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no red accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible red accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_ACCUM_GREEN_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no green accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible green accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_ACCUM_BLUE_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no blue accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible blue accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_ACCUM_ALPHA_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, frame buffer configurations with no alpha accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible alpha accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred. The default value is 0.

GLX_RENDER_TYPE

Must be followed by a mask indicating which OpenGL rendering modes the frame buffer configuration must support. Valid bits are GLX_RGBA_BIT and GLX_COLOR_INDEX_BIT. If the mask is set to GLX_RGBA_BIT | GLX_COLOR_INDEX_BIT, then only frame buffer configurations that can be bound to both RGBA contexts and color index contexts will be considered. The default value is GLX_RGBA_BIT.

GLX_DRAWABLE_TYPE

Must be followed by a mask indicating which GLX drawable types the frame buffer configuration must support. Valid bits are GLX_WINDOW_BIT, GLX_PIXMAP_BIT, and GLX_PBUFFER_BIT. For example, if mask is set to GLX_WINDOW_BIT | GLX_PIXMAP_BIT, only frame buffer configurations that support both windows and GLX pixmaps will be considered. The default value is GLX_WINDOW_BIT.

GLX_X_RENDERABLE

Must be followed by True or False. If True is specified, then only frame buffer configurations that have associated X visuals (and can be used to render to Windows and/or GLX pixmaps) will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE.

GLX_X_VISUAL_TYPE

Must be followed by one of GLX_TRUE_COLOR, GLX_DIRECT_COLOR, GLX_PSEUDO_COLOR, GLX_STATIC_COLOR, GLX_GRAY_SCALE, or GLX_STATIC_GRAY, indicating the desired X visual type. Not all frame buffer configurations have an associated X visual. If GLX_DRAWABLE_TYPE is specified in attrib_list and the mask that follows does not have GLX_WINDOW_BIT set, then this value is ignored. It is also ignored if GLX_X_RENDERABLE is specified as False. RGBA rendering may be supported for visuals of type GLX_TRUE_COLOR, GLX_DIRECT_COLOR, GLX_PSEUDO_COLOR, or GLX_STATIC_COLOR, but color index rendering is only supported for visuals of type GLX_PSEUDO_COLOR or GLX_STATIC_COLOR (i.e., single-channel visuals). The tokens GLX_GRAY_SCALE and GLX_STATIC_GRAY will not match current OpenGL enabled visuals, but are included for future use. The default value for GLX_X_VISUAL_TYPE is GLX_DONT_CARE.

GLX_CONFIG_CAVEAT

Must be followed by one of GLX_NONE, GLX_SLOW_CONFIG, GLX_NON_CONFORMANT_CONFIG. If GLX_NONE is specified, then only frame buffer configurations with no caveats will be considered; if GLX_SLOW_CONFIG is specified, then only slow frame buffer configurations will be considered; if GLX_NON_CONFORMANT_CONFIG is specified, then only nonconformant frame buffer configurations will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_TYPE

Must be followed by one of GLX_NONE, GLX_TRANSPARENT_RGB, GLX_TRANSPARENT_INDEX. If GLX_NONE is specified, then only opaque frame buffer configurations will be considered; if GLX_TRANSPARENT_RGB is specified, then only transparent frame buffer configurations that support RGBA rendering will be considered; if GLX_TRANSPARENT_INDEX is specified, then only transparent frame buffer configurations that support color index rendering will be considered. The default value is GLX_NONE.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_INDEX_VALUE

Must be followed by an integer value indicating the transparent index value; the value must be between 0 and the maximum frame buffer value for indices. Only frame buffer configurations that use the specified transparent index value will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE. This attribute is ignored unless GLX_TRANSPARENT_TYPE is included in attrib_list and specified as GLX_TRANSPARENT_INDEX.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_RED_VALUE

Must be followed by an integer value indicating the transparent red value; the value must be between 0 and the maximum frame buffer value for red. Only frame buffer configurations that use the specified transparent red value will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE. This attribute is ignored unless GLX_TRANSPARENT_TYPE is included in attrib_list and specified as GLX_TRANSPARENT_RGB.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_GREEN_VALUE

Must be followed by an integer value indicating the transparent green value; the value must be between 0 and the maximum frame buffer value for green. Only frame buffer configurations that use the specified transparent green value will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE. This attribute is ignored unless GLX_TRANSPARENT_TYPE is included in attrib_list and specified as GLX_TRANSPARENT_RGB.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_BLUE_VALUE

Must be followed by an integer value indicating the transparent blue value; the value must be between 0 and the maximum frame buffer value for blue. Only frame buffer configurations that use the specified transparent blue value will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE. This attribute is ignored unless GLX_TRANSPARENT_TYPE is included in attrib_list and specified as GLX_TRANSPARENT_RGB.

GLX_TRANSPARENT_ALPHA_VALUE

Must be followed by an integer value indicating the transparent alpha value; the value must be between 0 and the maximum frame buffer value for alpha. Only frame buffer configurations that use the specified transparent alpha value will be considered. The default value is GLX_DONT_CARE.

When more than one GLX frame buffer configuration matches the specified attributes, a list of matching configurations is returned. The list is sorted according to the following precedence rules, which are applied in ascending order (i.e., configurations that are considered equal by a lower numbered rule are sorted by the higher numbered rule):

1.

By GLX_CONFIG_CAVEAT where the precedence is GLX_NONE, GLX_SLOW_CONFIG, and GLX_NON_CONFORMANT_CONFIG.

2.

Larger total number of RGBA color components (GLX_RED_SIZE, GLX_GREEN_SIZE, GLX_BLUE_SIZE, plus GLX_ALPHA_SIZE) that have higher number of bits. If the requested number of bits in attrib_list is zero or GLX_DONT_CARE for a particular color component, then the number of bits for that component is not considered.

3.

Smaller GLX_BUFFER_SIZE.

4.

Single buffered configuration (GLX_DOUBLEBUFFER being False precedes a double buffered one.

5.

Smaller GLX_AUX_BUFFERS.

6.

Larger GLX_DEPTH_SIZE.

7.

Smaller GLX_STENCIL_SIZE.

8.

Larger total number of accumulation buffer color components (GLX_ACCUM_RED_SIZE, GLX_ACCUM_GREEN_SIZE, GLX_ACCUM_BLUE_SIZE, plus GLX_ACCUM_ALPHA_SIZE) that have higher number of bits. If the requested number of bits in attrib_list is zero or GLX_DONT_CARE for a particular color component, then the number of bits for that component is not considered.

9.

By GLX_X_VISUAL_TYPE where the precedence order is GLX_TRUE_COLOR, GLX_DIRECT_COLOR, GLX_PSEUDO_COLOR, GLX_STATIC_COLOR, GLX_GRAY_SCALE, GLX_STATIC_GRAY.

Examples

attrib_list =

{GLX_RENDER_TYPE, GLX_RGBA_BIT, GLX_RED_SIZE, 4, GLX_GREEN_SIZE, 4, GLX_BLUE_SIZE, 4, None};

Specifies a frame buffer configuration that supports RGBA rendering and exists in the normal frame buffer, not an overlay or underlay buffer. The returned visual supports at least four bits each of red, green, and blue, and possibly no bits of alpha. It does not support stereo display. It may or may not have one or more auxiliary color buffers, a back buffer, a depth buffer, a stencil buffer, or an accumulation buffer.

Notes

glXChooseFBConfig is available only if the GLX version is 1.3 or greater.

If the GLX version is 1.1 or 1.0, the GL version must be 1.0. If the GLX version is 1.2, then the GL version must be 1.1. If the GLX version is 1.3, then the GL version must be 1.2.

glXGetFBConfigs and glXGetFBConfigAttrib can be used to implement selection algorithms other than the generic one implemented by glXChooseFBConfig. Call glXChooseFBConfig to retrieve all the frame buffer configurations on a particular screen or, alternatively, all the frame buffer configurations with a particular set of attributes. Next, call glXGetFBConfigAttrib to retrieve additional attributes for the frame buffer configurations and then select between them.

GLX implementations are strongly discouraged, but not proscribed, from changing the selection algorithm used by glXChooseFBConfig. Therefore, selections may change from release to release of the client-side library.

Errors

NULL is returned if an undefined GLX attribute is encountered in attrib_list, if screen is invalid, or if dpy does not support the GLX extension.

See Also

glXGetFBConfigAttrib, glXGetFBConfigs, glXGetVisualFromFBConfig

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXChooseVisual — return a visual that matches specified attributes

C Specification

XVisualInfo* glXChooseVisual( | Display *   | dpy,
  | int   | screen,
  | int *   | attribList);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

screen

Specifies the screen number.

attribList

Specifies a list of boolean attributes and integer attribute/value pairs. The last attribute must be None.

Description

glXChooseVisual returns a pointer to an XVisualInfo structure describing the visual that best meets a minimum specification. The boolean GLX attributes of the visual that is returned will match the specified values, and the integer GLX attributes will meet or exceed the specified minimum values. If all other attributes are equivalent, then TrueColor and PseudoColor visuals have priority over DirectColor and StaticColor visuals, respectively. If no conforming visual exists, NULL is returned. To free the data returned by this function, use XFree.

All boolean GLX attributes default to False except GLX_USE_GL, which defaults to True. All integer GLX attributes default to zero. Default specifications are superseded by attributes included in attribList. Boolean attributes included in attribList are understood to be True. Integer attributes and enumerated type attributes are followed immediately by the corresponding desired or minimum value. The list must be terminated with None.

The interpretations of the various GLX visual attributes are as follows:

GLX_USE_GL

Ignored. Only visuals that can be rendered with GLX are considered.

GLX_BUFFER_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired color index buffer size. The smallest index buffer of at least the specified size is preferred. Ignored if GLX_RGBA is asserted.

GLX_LEVEL

Must be followed by an integer buffer-level specification. This specification is honored exactly. Buffer level zero corresponds to the main frame buffer of the display. Buffer level one is the first overlay frame buffer, level two the second overlay frame buffer, and so on. Negative buffer levels correspond to underlay frame buffers.

GLX_RGBA

If present, only TrueColor and DirectColor visuals are considered. Otherwise, only PseudoColor and StaticColor visuals are considered.

GLX_DOUBLEBUFFER

If present, only double-buffered visuals are considered. Otherwise, only single-buffered visuals are considered.

GLX_STEREO

If present, only stereo visuals are considered. Otherwise, only monoscopic visuals are considered.

GLX_AUX_BUFFERS

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired number of auxiliary buffers. Visuals with the smallest number of auxiliary buffers that meets or exceeds the specified number are preferred.

GLX_RED_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, the smallest available red buffer is preferred. Otherwise, the largest available red buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_GREEN_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, the smallest available green buffer is preferred. Otherwise, the largest available green buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_BLUE_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, the smallest available blue buffer is preferred. Otherwise, the largest available blue buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_ALPHA_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, the smallest available alpha buffer is preferred. Otherwise, the largest available alpha buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_DEPTH_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, visuals with no depth buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest available depth buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_STENCIL_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative integer that indicates the desired number of stencil bitplanes. The smallest stencil buffer of at least the specified size is preferred. If the desired value is zero, visuals with no stencil buffer are preferred.

GLX_ACCUM_RED_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, visuals with no red accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible red accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_ACCUM_GREEN_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, visuals with no green accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible green accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_ACCUM_BLUE_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, visuals with no blue accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible blue accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

GLX_ACCUM_ALPHA_SIZE

Must be followed by a nonnegative minimum size specification. If this value is zero, visuals with no alpha accumulation buffer are preferred. Otherwise, the largest possible alpha accumulation buffer of at least the minimum size is preferred.

Examples

attribList =

{GLX_RGBA, GLX_RED_SIZE, 4, GLX_GREEN_SIZE, 4, GLX_BLUE_SIZE, 4, None};

Specifies a single-buffered RGB visual in the normal frame buffer, not an overlay or underlay buffer. The returned visual supports at least four bits each of red, green, and blue, and possibly no bits of alpha. It does not support color index mode, double-buffering, or stereo display. It may or may not have one or more auxiliary color buffers, a depth buffer, a stencil buffer, or an accumulation buffer.

Notes

XVisualInfo is defined in Xutil.h. It is a structure that includes visual, visualID, screen, and depth elements.

glXChooseVisual is implemented as a client-side utility using only XGetVisualInfo and glXGetConfig. Calls to these two routines can be used to implement selection algorithms other than the generic one implemented by glXChooseVisual.

GLX implementations are strongly discouraged, but not proscribed, from changing the selection algorithm used by glXChooseVisual. Therefore, selections may change from release to release of the client-side library.

There is no direct filter for picking only visuals that support GLXPixmaps. GLXPixmaps are supported for visuals whose GLX_BUFFER_SIZE is one of the pixmap depths supported by the X server.

Errors

NULL is returned if an undefined GLX attribute is encountered in attribList.

See Also

glXCreateContext, glXGetConfig

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXCreateContext — create a new GLX rendering context

C Specification

GLXContext glXCreateContext( | Display *   | dpy,
  | XVisualInfo *   | vis,
  | GLXContext   | shareList,
  | Bool   | direct);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

vis

Specifies the visual that defines the frame buffer resources available to the rendering context. It is a pointer to an XVisualInfo structure, not a visual ID or a pointer to a Visual.

shareList

Specifies the context with which to share display lists. NULL indicates that no sharing is to take place.

direct

Specifies whether rendering is to be done with a direct connection to the graphics system if possible (True) or through the X server (False).

Description

glXCreateContext creates a GLX rendering context and returns its handle. This context can be used to render into both windows and GLX pixmaps. If glXCreateContext fails to create a rendering context, NULL is returned.

If direct is True, then a direct rendering context is created if the implementation supports direct rendering, if the connection is to an X server that is local, and if a direct rendering context is available. (An implementation may return an indirect context when direct is True.) If direct is False, then a rendering context that renders through the X server is always created. Direct rendering provides a performance advantage in some implementations. However, direct rendering contexts cannot be shared outside a single process, and they may be unable to render to GLX pixmaps.

If shareList is not NULL, then all display-list indexes and definitions are shared by context shareList and by the newly created context. An arbitrary number of contexts can share a single display-list space. However, all rendering contexts that share a single display-list space must themselves exist in the same address space. Two rendering contexts share an address space if both are nondirect using the same server, or if both are direct and owned by a single process. Note that in the nondirect case, it is not necessary for the calling threads to share an address space, only for their related rendering contexts to share an address space.

If the GL version is 1.1 or greater, then all texture objects except object 0 are shared by any contexts that share display lists.

Notes

XVisualInfo is defined in Xutil.h. It is a structure that includes visual, visualID, screen, and depth elements.

A process is a single execution environment, implemented in a single address space, consisting of one or more threads.

A thread is one of a set of subprocesses that share a single address space, but maintain separate program counters, stack spaces, and other related global data. A thread that is the only member of its subprocess group is equivalent to a process.

It may not be possible to render to a GLX pixmap with a direct rendering context.

Errors

NULL is returned if execution fails on the client side.

BadMatch is generated if the context to be created would not share the address space or the screen of the context specified by shareList.

BadValue is generated if vis is not a valid visual (for example, if a particular GLX implementation does not support it).

GLXBadContext is generated if shareList is not a GLX context and is not NULL.

BadAlloc is generated if the server does not have enough resources to allocate the new context.

See Also

glXDestroyContext, glXGetConfig, glXIsDirect, glXMakeCurrent

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXCreatePbuffer — create an off-screen rendering area

C Specification

GLXPbuffer glXCreatePbuffer( | Display *   | dpy,
  | GLXFBConfig   | config,
  | const int *   | attrib_list);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

config

Specifies a GLXFBConfig structure with the desired attributes for the window.

attrib_list

Specifies a list of attribute value pairs, which must be terminated with None or NULL. Accepted attributes are GLX_PBUFFER_WIDTH, GLX_PBUFFER_HEIGHT, GLX_PRESERVED_CONTENTS, and GLX_LARGEST_PBUFFER.

Description

glXCreatePbuffer creates an off-screen rendering area and returns its XID. Any GLX rendering context that was created with respect to config can be used to render into this window. Use glXMakeContextCurrent to associate the rendering area with a GLX rendering context.

The accepted attributes for a GLXPbuffer are:

GLX_PBUFFER_WIDTH

Specify the pixel width of the requested GLXPbuffer. The default value is 0.

GLX_PBUFFER_HEIGHT

Specify the pixel height of the requested GLXPbuffer. The default value is 0.

GLX_LARGEST_PBUFFER

Specify to obtain the largest available pixel buffer, if the requested allocation would have failed. The width and height of the allocated pixel buffer will never exceed the specified GLX_PBUFFER_WIDTH or GLX_PBUFFER_HEIGHT, respectively. Use glXQueryDrawable to retrieve the dimensions of the allocated pixel buffer. The default value is False.

GLX_PRESERVED_CONTENTS

Specify if the contents of the pixel buffer should be preserved when a resource conflict occurs. If set to False, the contents of the pixel buffer may be lost at any time. If set to True, or not specified in attrib_list, then the contents of the pixel buffer will be preserved (most likely by copying the contents into main system memory from the frame buffer). In either case, the client can register (using glXSelectEvent, to receive pixel buffer clobber events that are generated when the pbuffer contents have been preserved or damaged.

GLXPbuffers contain the color and ancillary buffers specified by config. It is possible to create a pixel buffer with back buffers and to swap those buffers using glXSwapBuffers.

Notes

glXCreatePbuffer is available only if the GLX version is 1.3 or greater.

If the GLX version is 1.1 or 1.0, the GL version must be 1.0. If the GLX version is 1.2, then the GL version must be 1.1. If the GLX version is 1.3, then the GL version must be 1.2.

GLXPbuffers are allocated from frame buffer resources; applications should consider deallocating them when they are not in use.

Errors

BadAlloc is generated if there are insufficient resources to allocate the requested GLXPbuffer.

GLXBadFBConfig is generated if config is not a valid GLXFBConfig.

BadMatch is generated if config does not support rendering to pixel buffers (e.g., GLX_DRAWABLE_TYPE does not contain GLX_PBUFFER_BIT).

See Also

glXChooseFBConfig, glXCreatePbuffer, glXMakeContextCurrent, glXSelectEvent

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXIntro — Introduction to OpenGL in the X window system

Overview

OpenGL (called GL in other pages) is a high-performance 3D-oriented renderer. It is available in the X window system through the GLX extension. To determine whether the GLX extension is supported by an X server, and if so, what version is supported, call glXQueryExtension and glXQueryVersion.

GLX extended X servers make a subset of their visuals available for OpenGL rendering. Drawables created with these visual can also be rendered into using the core X renderer and or any other X extension that is compatible with all core X visuals.

GLX extends a drawable's standard color buffer with additional buffers. These buffers include back and auxiliary color buffers, a depth buffer, a stencil buffer, and a color accumulation buffer. Some or all of the buffers listed are included in each X visual that supports OpenGL.

GLX supports rendering into three types of drawables: windows, pixmaps, and pbuffers (pixel buffers). GLX windows and pixmaps are X resources, and capable of accepting core X rendering as well as OpenGL rendering. GLX-pbuffers are GLX only resources and might not accept core X rendering.

To render using OpenGL into a GLX drawable, you must determine the appropriate GLXFBConfig that supports the rendering features your application requires. glXChooseFBConfig returns a GLXFBConfig matching the required attributes or NULL if no match is found. A complete list of GLXFBConfigs supported by a server can be obtained by calling glXGetFBConfigs. Attributes of a particular GLXFBConfig can be queried by calling glXGetFBConfigAttrib.

For GLX windows and pixmaps, a suitable X drawable (using either XCreateWindow or XCreatePixmap, respectively) with a matching visual must be created first. Call glXGetVisualFromFBConfig to obtain the necessary XVisualInfo structure for creating the X drawable. For pbuffers, no underlying X drawable is required.

To create a GLX window from an X window, call glXCreateWindow. Likewise, to create a GLX pixmap, call glXCreatePixmap. Pbuffers are created by calling glXCreatePbuffer. Use glXDestroyWindow, glXDestroyPixmap, and glXDestroyPbuffer to release previously allocated resources.

A GLX context is required to bind OpenGL rendering to a GLX resource. A GLX resource and rendering context must have compatible GLXFBConfigs. To create a GLX context, call glXCreateNewContext. A context may be bound to a GLX drawable by using glXMakeContextCurrent. This context/drawable pair becomes the current context and current drawable, and is used by all OpenGL rendering commands until glXMakeContextCurrent is called with different arguments.

Both core X and OpenGL commands can be used to operate on drawables; however, the X and OpenGL command streams are not synchronized. Synchronization can be explicitly specified using by calling glXWaitGL, glXWaitX, XSync, and XFlush.

Examples

Below is a minimal example of creating an RGBA-format X window that's compatible with OpenGL using GLX 1.3 commands. The window is cleared to yellow when the program runs. The program does minimal error checking; all return values should be checked.

#include <stdio.h>
#include <stdlib.h>
#include <GL/gl.h>
#include <GL/glx.h>

int singleBufferAttributess[] = {
    GLX_DRAWABLE_TYPE, GLX_WINDOW_BIT,
    GLX_RENDER_TYPE,   GLX_RGBA_BIT,
    GLX_RED_SIZE,      1,   /* Request a single buffered color buffer */
    GLX_GREEN_SIZE,    1,   /* with the maximum number of color bits  */
    GLX_BLUE_SIZE,     1,   /* for each component                     */
    None
};

int doubleBufferAttributes[] = {
    GLX_DRAWABLE_TYPE, GLX_WINDOW_BIT,
    GLX_RENDER_TYPE,   GLX_RGBA_BIT,
    GLX_DOUBLEBUFFER,  True,  /* Request a double-buffered color buffer with */
    GLX_RED_SIZE,      1,     /* the maximum number of bits per component    */
    GLX_GREEN_SIZE,    1, 
    GLX_BLUE_SIZE,     1,
    None
};


static Bool WaitForNotify( Display *dpy, XEvent *event, XPointer arg ) {
    return (event->type == MapNotify) && (event->xmap.window == (Window) arg);
}
int main( int argc, char *argv[] )
{
    Display              *dpy;
    Window                xWin;
    XEvent                event;
    XVisualInfo          *vInfo;
    XSetWindowAttributes  swa;
    GLXFBConfig          *fbConfigs;
    GLXContext            context;
    GLXWindow             glxWin;
    int                   swaMask;
    int                   numReturned;
    int                   swapFlag = True;

    /* Open a connection to the X server */
    dpy = XOpenDisplay( NULL );
    if ( dpy == NULL ) {
        printf( "Unable to open a connection to the X server\n" );
        exit( EXIT_FAILURE );
    }

    /* Request a suitable framebuffer configuration - try for a double 
    ** buffered configuration first */
    fbConfigs = glXChooseFBConfig( dpy, DefaultScreen(dpy),
                                   doubleBufferAttributes, &numReturned );

    if ( fbConfigs == NULL ) {  /* no double buffered configs available */
      fbConfigs = glXChooseFBConfig( dpy, DefaultScreen(dpy),
                                     singleBufferAttributess, &numReturned );
      swapFlag = False;
    }

    /* Create an X colormap and window with a visual matching the first
    ** returned framebuffer config */
    vInfo = glXGetVisualFromFBConfig( dpy, fbConfigs[0] );

    swa.border_pixel = 0;
    swa.event_mask = StructureNotifyMask;
    swa.colormap = XCreateColormap( dpy, RootWindow(dpy, vInfo->screen),
                                    vInfo->visual, AllocNone );

    swaMask = CWBorderPixel | CWColormap | CWEventMask;

    xWin = XCreateWindow( dpy, RootWindow(dpy, vInfo->screen), 0, 0, 256, 256,
                          0, vInfo->depth, InputOutput, vInfo->visual,
                          swaMask, &swa );

    /* Create a GLX context for OpenGL rendering */
    context = glXCreateNewContext( dpy, fbConfigs[0], GLX_RGBA_TYPE,
				 NULL, True );

    /* Create a GLX window to associate the frame buffer configuration
    ** with the created X window */
    glxWin = glXCreateWindow( dpy, fbConfigs[0], xWin, NULL );
    
    /* Map the window to the screen, and wait for it to appear */
    XMapWindow( dpy, xWin );
    XIfEvent( dpy, &event, WaitForNotify, (XPointer) xWin );

    /* Bind the GLX context to the Window */
    glXMakeContextCurrent( dpy, glxWin, glxWin, context );

    /* OpenGL rendering ... */
    glClearColor( 1.0, 1.0, 0.0, 1.0 );
    glClear( GL_COLOR_BUFFER_BIT );

    glFlush();
    
    if ( swapFlag )
        glXSwapBuffers( dpy, glxWin );

    sleep( 10 );
    exit( EXIT_SUCCESS );
}
            

Notes

An X color map must be created and passed to XCreateWindow.

A GLX context must be created and bound to a GLX drawable before OpenGL commands can be executed. OpenGL commands executed while no context/drawable pair is current result in undefined behavior.

Exposure events indicate that all buffers associated with the specified window may be damaged and should be repainted. Although certain buffers of some visuals on some systems may never require repainting (the depth buffer, for example), it is incorrect to write a program assuming that these buffers will not be damaged.

GLX commands utilize XVisualInfo structures rather than pointers to visuals or visualIDs directly. XVisualInfo structures contain visual, visualID, screen, and depth elements, as well as other X-specific information.

Using GLX Extensions

All supported GLX extensions will have a corresponding definition in glx.h and a token in the extension string returned by glXQueryExtensionsString. For example, if the EXT_visual_info extension is supported, then this token will be defined in glx.h and EXT_visual_info will appear in the extension string returned by glXQueryExtensionsString. The definitions in glx.h can be used at compile time to determine if procedure calls corresponding to an extension exist in the library.

OpenGL itself is capable of being extended.

GLX 1.1, GLX 1.2, and GLX 1.3

GLX 1.3 is now supported and is backward compatible with GLX 1.1 and GLX 1.2. It introduces new functionality (namely GLXFBConfigs) that supersedes the GLX 1.2 functionality. GLX 1.2 commands are supported, but their use in new application development is not recommended.

GLX 1.3 corresponds to OpenGL versions 1.2 and introduces the following new calls: glXGetFBConfigs, glXGetFBConfigAttrib, glXGetVisualFromFBConfig, glXCreateWindow, glXDestroyWindow, glXCreatePixmap, glXDestroyPixmap, glXCreatePbuffer, glXDestroyPbuffer, glXQueryDrawable, glXCreateNewContext, glXMakeContextCurrent, glXGetCurrentReadDrawable, glXGetCurrentDisplay, glXQueryContext, and glXSelectEvent, glXGetSelectedEvent.

GLX 1.2 corresponds to OpenGL version 1.1 and introduces the following new call: glXGetCurrentDisplay.

GLX 1.1 corresponds to OpenGL version 1.0 and introduces the following new calls: glXQueryExtensionsString, glXQueryServerString, and glXGetClientString.

Call glXQueryVersion to determine at runtime what version of GLX is available. glXQueryVersion returns the version that is supported on the connection. Thus, if 1.3 is returned, both the client and server support GLX 1.3. You can also check the GLX version at compile time: GLX_VERSION_1_1 will be defined in glx.h if GLX 1.1 calls are supported, GLX_VERSION_1_2 will be defined if GLX 1.2 calls are supported, and GLX_VERSION_1_3 will be defined if GLX 1.3 calls are supported.

See Also

glFinish, glFlush, glXChooseVisual, glXCopyContext, glXCreateContext, glXCreateGLXPixmap, glXCreateNewContext, glXCreatePbuffer, glXCreatePixmap, glXCreateWindow, glXDestroyContext, glXDestroyPbuffer, glXDestroyPixmap, glXDestroyWindow, glXGetClientString, glXGetConfig, glXGetCurrentDisplay, glXGetCurrentReadDrawable, glXGetFBConfigAttrib, glXGetFBConfigs, glXGetProcAddress, glXGetSelectedEvent, glXGetVisualFromFBConfig, glXIsDirect, glXMakeContextCurrent, glXMakeCurrent, glXQueryContext, glXQueryDrawable, glXQueryExtension, glXQueryExtensionsString, glXQueryServerString, glXQueryVersion, glXSelectEvent, glXSwapBuffers, glXUseXFont, glXWaitGL, glXWaitX. XCreateColormap, XCreateWindow, XSync

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.

Name

glXSwapBuffers — exchange front and back buffers

C Specification

void glXSwapBuffers( | Display *   | dpy,
  | GLXDrawable   | drawable);

Parameters

dpy

Specifies the connection to the X server.

drawable

Specifies the drawable whose buffers are to be swapped.

Description

glXSwapBuffers promotes the contents of the back buffer of drawable to become the contents of the front buffer of drawable. The contents of the back buffer then become undefined. The update typically takes place during the vertical retrace of the monitor, rather than immediately after glXSwapBuffers is called.

glXSwapBuffers performs an implicit glFlush before it returns. Subsequent OpenGL commands may be issued immediately after calling glXSwapBuffers, but are not executed until the buffer exchange is completed.

If drawable was not created with respect to a double-buffered visual, glXSwapBuffers has no effect, and no error is generated.

Notes

The contents of the back buffer become undefined after a swap. Note that this applies to pixel buffers as well as windows.

All GLX rendering contexts share the same notion of which are front buffers and which are back buffers. One consequence is that when multiple clients are rendering to the same double-buffered window, all of them should finish rendering before one of them issues the command to swap buffers. The clients are responsible for implementing this synchronization. Typically this is accomplished by executing glFinish and then using a semaphore in shared memory to rendezvous before swapping.

Errors

GLXBadDrawable is generated if drawable is not a valid GLX drawable.

GLXBadCurrentWindow is generated if dpy and drawable are respectively the display and drawable associated with the current context of the calling thread, and drawable identifies a window that is no longer valid.

See Also

glFlush

Copyright

Copyright © 1991-2006 Silicon Graphics, Inc. This document is licensed under the SGI Free Software B License. For details, see http://oss.sgi.com/projects/FreeB/.